{
    "id": "269682e9aec841b587abeaddc04aaafc",
    "title": "Would, Used To Or Simple Past",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "35a4963377f1438a976557dc39ed7375",
            "title": "Would, Used To Or Simple Past",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "He …………….. smoke but now he has stopped.",
                    "description": "We use used to talk about past habits and states.",
                    "answers": [
                        "would",
                        "used to",
                        "smoked"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She ……….. always bring us nice gifts.",
                    "description": "Both would and used to can be used to talk about repeated actions in the past.",
                    "answers": [
                        "used to",
                        "would",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………… go skiing but now I don’t.",
                    "description": "We use 'used to' to talk about past states. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "used to",
                        "would",
                        "was used to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "You used to hate him, ……………….?",
                    "description": "Used to is not used in the question tags. We use 'did' here because the statement is in the past tense. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "used you not",
                        "don't you",
                        "didn't you"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………….. play basketball at college?",
                    "description": "In a formal style, used to is often used as a modal auxiliary verb. In this case, questions and negatives are made without do. In an informal style we make questions and negatives with do.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Used you to",
                        "Did you use to",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………… like classical music, but now I do.",
                    "description": "When we make negatives, not can go before or after to. Did not use to is also possible here in an informal style. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "did not use to",
                        "used not to",
                        "used to not",
                        "All of the above"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "I …………………. have any interest in politics.",
                    "description": "Did not use to and used not to are possible here. Did not used to is not considered correct. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "did not use to",
                        "did not used to",
                        "used not to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I …………….. in Mumbai for 13 years.",
                    "description": "We do not use ‘used to’ to simply say what happened at a past time or how long it took. Those meanings are expressed with the simple past.",
                    "answers": [
                        "lived",
                        "would live",
                        "used to live"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………… be afraid of dogs.",
                    "description": "Would cannot be used to talk about past states.",
                    "answers": [
                        "would",
                        "used to",
                        "was used to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I couldn’t understand them because I ………………… their accent.",
                    "description": "If you are not used to something, it is not familiar to you.",
                    "answers": [
                        "didn't use to",
                        "wasn't used to",
                        "used wasn't to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It took me quite some time to get ………………… alone.",
                    "description": "We use an ing form after get used to. The infinitive is not possible in this structure.",
                    "answers": [
                        "used to live",
                        "used to living",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I …………….. to London twice last month.",
                    "description": "We do not use ‘used to’ to simply say what happened at a past time or how long it took. Those meanings are expressed with the simple past.",
                    "answers": [
                        "used to go",
                        "would go",
                        "went"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}